Register of the Julean Herbert Arnold papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Julean Herbert Arnold papers
1905-1946
73013
Hoover Institution Archives
14 manuscript boxes, 3 envelopes (6.2 linear feet)
Diary, correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, dispatches, instructions, and memoranda relating to the American consular service in China, economic and political developments in China, and American commercial and foreign policy in East Asia. Digital copy of Arnold's diary also available at http://digitalcollections.hoover.org
Arnold, Julean Herbert, 1875-1946.
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copy of Arnold's diary also available at http://digitalcollections.hoover.org
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1973.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copy of Arnold's diary also available at http://digitalcollections.hoover.org
Biographical Note
1876 July 19 Born, Sacramento, California
1902 B.S., California College of Commerce
1904-1914 U.S. Consular Service in China
1914-1917 U.S. Commercial Attaché in China and Japan
1917-1940 U.S. Commercial Attaché in China
1915 Founder, American Chamber of Commerce, Shanghai
1915 Delegate, Pan-Pacific Commercial Conference, Honolulu
1916 Founder, China Club of Seattle
1918, 1922, 1926-1927 Chairman, American Delegation to China Tariff Revision Commission, Shanghai
1926 Author, China: A Commercial and Industrial Handbook
1928 Author, Some Bigger Issues in China's Problems
1932 Author, China Through the American Window
1946 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
Diary, correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, dispatches, instructions, and memoranda relating to the American consular service in China, economic and political developments in China, and American commercial and foreign policy in East Asia.
United States. Department of State.; China--Economic conditions.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--Politics and government--20th century.; United States--Commerce.; United States--Foreign relations--China.
- DIARY, 1926-1927, 1932-1937 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Diary and diary notes, arranged chronologically.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1916-1946 (Box 1)
  Correspondence, arranged chronologically within the folder labeled "General" and alphabetically by last name of correspondent for the remaining folders.
  - General (Box 1)
  - Bloom, Sol
  - Dennis, William H.
  - Hart, Walter M.
  - Hornbeck, Stanley K.
  - Johnson, Luther A.
  - Johnson, Nelson T.
  - Kung, H. H.
  - McCoy, Frank R.
  - MacMurray, J. V. A.
  - Millard, Thomas F.
  - Patterson, Richard C.
  - Peck, Willys R.
  - Pierson, Warren L.
  - Pott, F. L. Hawke
  - Sproul, Robert G.
  - Sun Yat Sen
  - Swan, J. E.
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1909-1946 (Boxes 1-3)
  Drafts and printed copies of speeches and writings, arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Address before the Credit Managers Association of Northern and Central California, 1945 (Box 1)
  - "America and a Japanese China,", 1941
  - "America in China,", 1937
  - "America Must Become Pacific Minded"
  - "American Interests in China"
  - "American Prestige and Influence in China"
  - "American Schools in China"
  - "American Trade in China,", 1915
  - "American Trade Prospects with China,", 1934
  - "American Trade Relations with China"
  - "America's Concern Over What Happens in China"
  - "America's Policy Toward China,", 1946
  - "America's Stake in China,", 1938
  - "Agriculture in the Economic Life of the New China,", 1923
  - "Asia Houses for Pacific Coast Ports,", 1936
  - "Asiatic Conditions,", 1941
  - "Behind Those Chinese Lines,", 1941
  - "California's Altar of Heaven Debating Trophy"
  - "Can China Meet the Challenge?"
  - "Can the Small Business Man Survive?,", 1937
  - "Changing China"
  - "Chicago's Post-War Stake in China,", 1941
  - "China--,", 1923
  - "China: A Challenge,", 1945
  - "China-American Trade Notes"
  - "China: America's Brightest Hope"
  - "China: America's Brightest Post-war Outlook,", 1944
  - "China: Can Do,", 1944
  - "China: Challenge to America"
  - "China in America,", 1926
  - "China Is Calling,", 1944
  - "China: Our Best New Source of Wealth,", 1944
  - "China: Our New World of Opportunity"
  - "China Supersensitive Nationalism" (Box 2)
  - "China Trade Facts,", 1925
  - "China's Billion Dollar Exports to America"
  - "China's Fate and America's Future,", 1939
  - "China's Geographic Foundations,", 1934
  - "China's Industrialization"
  - "China's Prewar Trade,", 1944
  - "China's Railways--Present and in the Post-war Future,", 1943
  - "Chinese and American Inter-marriages"
  - "Chinese and the American Business Man"
  - "Chinese Compradore"
  - "Chinese Sports and Sportsmanship"
  - Digest of Julean Arnold's statement before the Foreign Affairs Committee, 1939 May 4
  - "Do Our China Missionaries Merit Your Support?,", 1941
  - "Educating Chinese in America"
  - "Education in the Philippine Islands"
  - "Effect of Sino-Japanese Crisis Upon the Future of America"
  - "Foreign Trade Week for China,", 1937
  - "Future of America in China"
  - "Guild Terrorism"
  - "How American Merchants and Manufacturers May Enter China,", 1916
  - "How Can Our Movie Films Help Our Trade with China?"
  - "If I Were a Chinese,", 1946
  - "Industry Invasion,", 1923
  - "Inland Banking Facilities"
  - "Invasion of China Menaces America"
  - "Is America an Ally of Japan?,", 1938
  - "Is Japan Blasting America Out of the Pacific?"
  - "Is Japan Blitzkrieging America Out of the Pacific?,", 1940
  - "Jade,", 1936
  - "Japanese Attitude toward American Interests in China"
  - "Japanese Bull in a China Shop"
  - "Japanese Goodwill Mission to America,", 1939
  - "Japan's Policies and American Interest,", 1938
  - "Japanese Victory and U.S. Labor"
  - "Know China!"
  - "Learn to Know China First"
  - Lecture given at Ford Ord, 1944 October 25
  - "Making the Shanghai American Chamber of Commerce More Effective"
  - "Message to the People of China,", 1942
  - "Millions for Educating the East to Know the West but Not One Cent to Train the West to Know the East,", 1924
  - "Missionary's Opportunity,", 1941
  - "Museum Method of Introducing American Goods into China,", 1916
  - "New Scenic China,", 1937
  - "Notes for 'Home and Abroad' from Shanghai Office,", 1936
  - "Opportunities in Post-war China"
  - "Our Far Eastern Problem"
  - "Our Missionaries--Assets or Liabilities?,", 1941
  - "Our Neighbors Across the Pacific"
  - "Our Opportunity Lies Westward"
  - "Our Stake in the Future of China,", 1943
  - "Our Trade with China"
  - Outline of talk at Hammond Hospital, Modesto, California, 1944 November 2
  - "Pacific--Ocean of Destiny" (Box 3)
  - "Peoples of Formosa,", 1909
  - "Post-war China--Our Best Bet"
  - "Post-war Merchant Marine, Benefits Counted"
  - "Proposed 'China House,' 'Asia House,' or 'House of the Orient' for Pacific Coast Ports,", 1934
  - Review of Albert Herrmann's Atlas of China
  - "Salient Facts in China's Trade"
  - "Shanghai Under Fire"
  - "Should the U.S. Get Out of China?,", 1938
  - "Silent Ambassadors,", 1932
  - "Some Bigger Issues in China's Problems,", 1929
  - "Student Interpreters and Language Attachés"
  - "Suggestions for Revitalizing the Department of Commerce"
  - "They Thought China Had Nothing to Teach Them"
  - "Tragedy of Ignorance"
  - "Training Americans to Know Asia"
  - "Tung Oil Industry Developments in United States,", 1933
  - "Twenty-eight Suggestions for Improving American-Chinese Trade Relations,", 1930
  - "Unique Institution with a Unique Opportunity,", 1929
  - "U.S. and China in the Post-war World"
  - "Walking to My Office in Shanghai"
  - "Western Characteristics Needed in China,", 1910
  - "Western Educated Student's Opportunity in the Commercial Life of the New China"
  - "What Can China Mean to America?,", 1943
  - "What China Yields in Peace and War"
  - "What Does China's Modernization Mean to Us?,", 1942
  - "What Shall We Do about It?"
  - "What Will a Japanese Victory Mean to American Cotton?"
  - "What Would a Japanese Victory in China Mean to America?,", 1939
  - "Whither Do We Go?,", 1938
  - "Why an American Mercantile Marine?"
  - "Why Worry About China?,", 1941
  - "Yankee Clipper Returns"
  - Notes
  - Invitations and appreciations for speaking engagements
- OFFICE FILE, 1905-1940 (Boxes 4-11)
  Reports, despatches, instructions, correspondence, memoranda, lists, scrapbook, and printed matter, arranged by subseries. The offices and positions held by Julean Arnold, including American Assessor for the International Mixed Court, U.S. Consul in China, and U.S. Commercial Attaché in China, constitute the subseries.
  - American Assessor, International Mixed Court (Box 4)
    - Report on Interference of the Shanghai Municipal Council in Matters Pertaining to the International Mixed Court, 1905-1906
  - U.S. Consul in China (Amoy)
    - Reports on Tours Across West China, 1910
  - U.S. Commercial Attaché in China
    - List of Reporting Section staff
    - Despatches and weekly reports to the Bureau of Foreign and Domestic Commerce, Department of Commerce
      - 1915-1919
      - 1918-1920
      - 1920-1925
      - 1926-1927
      - 1926-1927 (Box 5)
      - 1928-1930
      - 1928-1931
      - 1932-1934 (Box 6)
      - 1932-1937
      - 1932-1934 (Box 7)
      - 1937
      - 1938
      - 1939-1940
    - Confidential correspondence and cables, 1921-1929
      Declassified U.S. government records returned to file after July 2015 release by Hoover.
    - Special correspondence and despatches, 1926-1929
    - China Monthly Trade Report (Peking - Shanghai), 1929 (Box 8)
    - Scrapbook, 1936-1937
    - Information and correspondence file on China (Box 9)
      - Agriculture
      - American firms in China
      - American shipping in China
      - Chinese Chamber of Commerce
      - Commerce and trade
      - Communications
      - Economy, general
      - Education
      - German involvement in China
      - Industrial cooperatives
      - Industrialization
      - Japan's involvement in China, 1914-1940 (Box 10)
      - Labor conditions
      - Newspapers
      - Political conditions
      - Status of Commercial Attaché and relationship with State Department
      - Trade promotion by U.S.
      - Transportation (Box 11)
      - U.S. foreign policy in China
      - Vital statistics
    - Retirement of Julean Arnold, 1940
- SUBJECT FILE, 1941-1946 (Boxes 11-13)
  Correspondence, reports, newsletters, lists, clippings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - American Chambers of Commerce in China (Box 11)
  - California College in China Foundation, 1945-1946
  - China
    - General
    - General (Box 12)
    - Art and literature
    - Bibliographies
  - China-America Council of Commerce and Industry, 1944-1946
  - China Club of Seattle, 1945-1946
  - China Commerce Club of California
  - China Information Committee
  - China Institute in America, 1941-1946
  - China Society of America, 1944-1946
  - Chinese Exclusion Act, repeal of, 1942-1944 (Box 13)
  - Chinese in the U.S.
  - Chinese national anthem
  - Japan, general
  - Soybean protein
  - United China Relief, 1944-1946
  - United National Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1944-1946
- MISCELLANY (Box 14)
  Clippings, mailing lists and calling cards, maps, memorabilia, and miscellaneous printed matter, arranged as listed.
  - Clippings about Julean Arnold (Box 14)
  - Mailing lists and calling cards
  - Maps
  - Memorabilia
  - Printed matter
- PHOTOGRAPHS (Photo file)
  96 prints / 3 envelopes.
  - 25 photos of maps of China, of a U.S. trade display in Shanghai, and of Julean Arnold and family (Envelope A)
  - 40 photos of scenes of daily life in China, including photos and drawings of typical Chinese tools (Envelope B)
  - 1 photo and 30 ink drawings of Chinese trade products (Envelope C)